{
  "topic_id":"114",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "This is very heady punch, so watch your step.",
      "choice": ["Simple sentence", "Complex sentence", "Compound sentence"],
      "answer": 2,
      "explanation": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses.",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "I don’t know what I should do now.",
      "choice": ["Simple sentence", "Complex sentence", "Compound sentence"],
      "answer": 1,
      "explanation": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "The helicopter hovered over the house.",
      "choice": ["Simple sentence", "Complex sentence", "Compound sentence"],
      "answer": 0,
      "explanation": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "A howl of protest went up when the voting was announced.",
      "choice": ["Simple sentence", "Complex sentence", "Compound sentence"],
      "answer": 1,
      "explanation": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "He became rich through wise investments.",
      "choice": ["Simple sentence", "Complex sentence", "Compound sentence"],
      "answer": 0,
      "explanation": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What type of sentence is this?\n I absolutely love to see the lion tamer perform!",
      "choice": ["declarative", "imperative", "interrogative", "exclamatory"],
      "answer": 3,
      "explanation": "",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Read the following sentence and identify the sentence type:\n Pauline loves to go to the beach and spend her days sunbathing.",
      "choice": [
        "Simple sentence",
        "Complex sentence",
        "Compound sentence",
        "compound-complex sentence"
      ],
      "answer": 0,
      "explanation": "A simple sentence has just one subject and one predicate.",
      "keywords": [{ "sunbath": "የፀሐይ መታጠቢያ" }]
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Read the sentence and choose the answer that identifies the type of sentence:\n Before the sun rises, she runs two miles or exercises.",
      "choice": [
        "Simple sentence",
        "Complex sentence",
        "Compound sentence",
        "compound-complex sentence"
      ],
      "answer": 1,
      "explanation": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "A sentence with two or more independent, or main, clauses with two ideas of equal importance is called a",
      "choice": [
        "Simple sentence",
        "Complex sentence",
        "Compound sentence",
        "compound-complex sentence"
      ],
      "answer": 2,
      "explanation": "",
      "keywords": []
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Identify the sentence type.\nAfter school Christopher fed the snakes and Matthew looked after the guinea pigs.",
      "choice": [
        "Simple sentence",
        "Complex sentence",
        "Compound sentence",
        "compound-complex sentence"
      ],
      "answer": 2,
      "explanation": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses.",
      "keywords": [{ "snakes": "እባቦች" }, { "pigs": "አሳማዎች" }]
    }
  ]
}
